<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Santa Clara Real Estate Podcast with Brandon Montemayor</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Montemayor & Associates - your professional Santa Clara Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Brandon Montemayor</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-05-30 15:35:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Brandon Montemayor</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Brandon@bringingyouhomescv.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Santa Clara Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Montemayor & Associates - your professional Santa Clara Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>A 90-Day Recap of Our Santa Clarita Valley Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-90-day-recap-of-our-santa-clarita.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-23 15:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+A+90-Day+Recap+of+Our+Santa+Clarita+Valley+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What happened in our market these last 90 days?
Find out with this quick market update.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


Today we’re going to take a look at what’s going on in the Santa Clarita Valley area real estate market. While data relating to pending and active listings can give us a decent idea of current trends, the best way to get a feel for our market is by examining the homes that have actually sold.

In the last 90 days, we’ve had 921 properties sell in our area. Of those properties, 625 were single-family homes, while the remaining 296 were condos, townhomes, or manufactured dwellings.

Here is the full breakdown of homes sold by area:

Canyon Country - 216
Castaic - 78
Newhall - 96
Saugus - 204
Stevenson Ranch - 43
Valencia - 283
“Santa Clarita” - 1 (This home was actually in Canyon County, but was listed otherwise).

“The best way to get a feel for our market is by examining the homes that have actually sold.”

Looking at how these 921 properties broke down between price points, it’s clear that some ranges see more activity than others. Here is the full breakdown of homes sold per price point:

$300,000 and below - 48 homes
$300,000 to $450,000 - 220 homes
$450,000 to $600,000 - 334 homes
$600,000 to $750,000 - 219 homes
$750,000 to $900,000 - 64 homes
$900,000 to $1 million - 13 homes
$1 million and up - 23 homes

If you have any other questions or would like more information about what this data means for you and your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+A+90-Day+Recap+of+Our+Santa+Clarita+Valley+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+A+90-Day+Recap+of+Our+Santa+Clarita+Valley+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What happened in our market these last 90 days?
Find out with this quick market update.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What happened in our market these last 90 days?
Find out with this quick market update.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8 Simple Steps a Future Home Seller Can Take Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/8-simples-steps-future-home-seller-can.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-29 16:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+8+Simple+Steps+a+Future+Home+Seller+Can+Take+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

These eight easy, preparatory tips are sure to put any
future seller’s home in prime market condition.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


There’s a portion of sellers out there who know they want to list their home, but aren’t ready just yet. These same sellers wonder, though, what precursory steps they can take to ensure that they’re in good shape when the time to hit the market comes.

If this is true for your situation, here are eight easy steps you can take:

1. Have us come out to the house. We’ll draw up a very specific, specialized plan for you and your home so that you’re not spending time on items that won’t bring the value you might otherwise expect. Even if you’re five years away from your move, we’re always happy to come out and offer our opinion on what it’ll take to get your home market-ready.

2. Raise your home’s curb appeal. Think like a buyer who’s stepping onto your property for the first time—what would you want to see if you were them? Maybe you need to do away with some of those dead spots in your lawn, add some colorful flowers, remove an old tree stump or a shabby-looking chair. Whatever the case may be, this is a good place to start.

3. Declutter the interior of your home. Create a smooth, easy walkway for future buyers to come through. An environment where a buyer has to squeeze through tight or cluttered spaces won’t bode well for your sale, and wide open spaces tend to show better.

4. Repaint walls that may have an “extreme” color. Paint over lurid-colored walls with a more neutral option, and while you’re at it, touch up any nicks in the baseboards or on the walls. These sorts of things are the normal wear-and-tear of a lived-in home, but should be dealt with before your home goes to market.

“We’re always happy to come out and offer our opinion on what it’ll take to get your home market-ready.”

5. Put your home to the “smell test.” This may be a bit of a hit to the pride, but it’s important to have an unbiased, third-party come into your home and give you an honest opinion. They’ll pick up things you probably wouldn’t—pet odors, the lingering smells of your cooking, etc., can all affect the salability of your home. Knowing this up front could determine your course of action when it comes to painting or recarpeting as well.

6. Perform a deep-cleaning. Whether it’s getting up to your high windows or dusting off shutters at harder-to-reach points, it’s a good idea to thoroughly clean these areas so that your home shows well and gets through the inspection with flying colors.

7. Start to hide valuables. You should begin to box up and put away valuable belongings if you won’t be using them in the next year or so. This way, you’ll know these items are in safekeeping when buyers are walking through your home.

8. Begin the staging process. Bulky, large furniture might be great for your current living situation, but when it’s “show-time,” they might make the room feel smaller and more cluttered. Because of this, it’s best to take early steps to remove some of these items, widen the open space, and create a great flow.

We’d love to come out to your property and work with you to lay out a plan for your future sale. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to contact us. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+8+Simple+Steps+a+Future+Home+Seller+Can+Take+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+8+Simple+Steps+a+Future+Home+Seller+Can+Take+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

These eight easy, preparatory tips are sure to put any
future seller’s home in prime market condition.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

These eight easy, preparatory tips are sure to put any
future seller’s home in prime market condition.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Homeowners: Are Solar Panels a Good Idea?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/homeowners-are-solar-panels-good-idea.html</link>
        
          <category>Homeowner Tips</category>
        
          <category>Solar Energy</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-11 15:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Homeowners-+Are+Solar+Panels+a+Good+Idea_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Solar power is a popular topic lately. Today I’ll examine whether or not
installing solar panels on your home is a good idea.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


When talking about whether or not adding solar panels to your home is a good idea, there are two main points to think about.

First, ask yourself, “Do you plan on living in your home for a short period, or are you planning to live there long-term?”

For people who are looking to live in their home long-term, solar is a great idea.

If you’re only considering a short-term stay in that property, it really comes down to whether you can afford to put solar panels on the house and purchase it.

A leased solar panel tends to cause homebuyers some uncertainty; they don’t typically like to take on other people’s leases. Mind you, we’ve sold a ton of homes with solar leases, some within a few months after the selling process, but if you want to appeal to most homebuyers, a solar lease isn’t the way to go.

“For people who are looking to live in their home long-term, solar is a great idea.”

It’s much easier to sell a house where the solar panels are owned by the homeowner. There are no additional payments, and it provides immediate savings in terms of utilities if you didn’t have to invest in the system.

Now if you’re planning to stay in your home long-term and are considering purchasing solar panels, you need to think about your income. Do you have a relatively fixed income? How much money do you have in your savings?

If you’re on a fixed income, have some money in your savings, and you can afford to make an investment in your house, solar panels will help you save on your electric bill over time by bringing it down to almost nothing.

If you don’t have a ton of money in your savings but you do have a consistent income, a lease is a great idea. During the hotter summer months out here in Santa Clarita where temperatures get into the 100s, solar panels will help you save big time.

For any questions you have about solar panels, the logistics of having them installed, and/or the savings they’ll provide you, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to have an in-depth discussion with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Homeowners-+Are+Solar+Panels+a+Good+Idea_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Homeowners-+Are+Solar+Panels+a+Good+Idea_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Solar power is a popular topic lately. Today I’ll examine whether or not
installing solar panels on your home is a good idea.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Solar power is a popular topic lately. Today I’ll examine whether or not
installing solar panels on your home is a good idea.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your March Santa Clarita Valley Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-march-santa-clarita-valley-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-25 16:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What’s the latest in our Santa Clarita Valley market? Find out today.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


Over the last 10 years, our market has experienced extreme highs and extreme lows. Around 2007, it hit a peak and subsequently crashed, but it went back up a few years later. That upward momentum continued until around last year, when things began to flatten out.

Now, the market is forecasted to stay steady for one to two years. We’ll experience normal levels of appreciation between 2% and 4%, and there are two factors that indicate this: Inventory is still fairly low, though it’s growing in some areas, and so are interest rates. Since neither of these factors will change overnight, we can expect a consistent market for a while.

If you want to talk about buying or selling a home, have any questions, or need more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What’s the latest in our Santa Clarita Valley market? Find out today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What’s the latest in our Santa Clarita Valley market? Find out today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Markets Performance So Far in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-markets-performance-so-far-in-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-25 14:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Our+Markets+Performance+So+Far+in+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re curious about what market conditions are like in the early stages of 2019,
my latest market update will tell you all you need to know.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


It’s time to look at how our market is performing so far in the early part of 2019.

Let’s get right to it: As of now, our active inventory is at 557 homes throughout Santa Clarita Valley and 361 home sales are either pending or in escrow. Year to date, there has been a total of 288 closings.

As you can tell, our market is experiencing a general upturn, with more homes in escrow than what was true of the same time last year. However, active listings haven’t budged much from where they were a year ago.

“The marriage of amazingly low rates and our active listings leveling off is encouraging for the strength and stability of our current market.”

Interest rates have been tempered as well. In fact, we’ve seen some conventional loans as low as 4.5% as well as FHA and VA loans situated at 4.125%.

The marriage of amazingly low rates and our active listings leveling off—which means homes are still selling well—is encouraging for the strength and stability of our current market. This is to say that there are still moves to be made and plenty of opportunities to secure the best deal possible.

If you have any questions related to our real estate market and how it affects your personal situation, don’t hesitate to reach out. Put us to work for you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Our+Markets+Performance+So+Far+in+2019.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Our+Markets+Performance+So+Far+in+2019.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re curious about what market conditions are like in the early stages of 2019,
my latest market update will tell you all you need to know.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re curious about what market conditions are like in the early stages of 2019,
my latest market update will tell you all you need to know.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Team Has Moved & Our Current Market Is Doing the Same</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-team-has-moved-our-current-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-31 12:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Our+Team+Has+Moved+%26+Our+Current+Market+Is+Doing+the+Same.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our team has moved offices! Hear more about this and the
latest information regarding our current market in today’s message.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


Now that we’ve transitioned into 2019, we’re happy to announce that our team has also transitioned into a new office! Don’t worry, though—we have no plans to leave RE/MAX Santa Clarita. We have a great relationship with the company and an amazing support staff and system to serve our clients’ needs at the highest level.

The move wasn’t drastic by any means: We’re still on the same road between Lyons Avenue and Calgrove Boulevard, right off the 5 Freeway. We’ve gone from that white building into the big, brick building across from In-N-Out and the hotels nearby.

We look forward to doing some client events at our new location in the future, as well as bringing you more videos that’ll acquaint you with the new space and introduce you to everyone who’s hard at work to protect your real estate investments!

If you happen to be in the area and need anything from us, we’d love for you to drop in, say hello, and let us know how we can help.

“We’re happy to announce that our team has transitioned into a new office!”

For a moment, let’s turn our attention to the 2019 market and how it’s performing so far:

Though it was slow going as we entered the new year, our market has again begun to pick up speed. We’re seeing multiple-offer situations spring up, interest rates are staying at historic lows, and correctly priced homes are still selling for top dollar.

With the right amount of patience, some persistence, and a game plan, you can take advantage of what our market has to offer right now, and we’re here to assist you with that.

For help with any and all of your real estate needs, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We look forward to an awesome 2019 and to talking to you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Our+Team+Has+Moved+%26+Our+Current+Market+Is+Doing+the+Same.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Our+Team+Has+Moved+%26+Our+Current+Market+Is+Doing+the+Same.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our team has moved offices! Hear more about this and the
latest information regarding our current market in today’s message.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our team has moved offices! Hear more about this and the
latest information regarding our current market in today’s message.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ultimate Holiday Home Maintenance Checklist</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-ultimate-holiday-home-maintenance.html</link>
        
          <category>Homeowner Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Maintenance</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-04 16:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+The+Ultimate+Holiday+Home+Maintenance+Checklist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you taking proper care of your home? Follow this home maintenance checklist
to make sure that your property stays in the best shape possible.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


The holiday season is absolutely flying by. Before we know it, we’ll all be left scrambling to find space in our homes for all the gifts we received.

For some of you, this may mean taking a trip up to the attic or down to the basement. Coincidentally, the holiday season is also a perfect time to check on the vital home systems that run from those less-traveled places of your property. There’s no time like the present to get started on your home maintenance checklist.

If you aren’t sure where to begin, click here to see the list we’ve put together. Following the steps on this list will be crucial to keeping your home (and your family) safe and sound.

“Proper home maintenance will save you a lot of time, money, and hassle in the long run.”

Also, while larger tasks like checking up on your HVAC system, your hot water heater, and other major systems and appliances are important, you also shouldn’t neglect less-involved maintenance items, such as cleaning the gutters, replacing the batteries in your smoke detectors, and changing out your air filters. Proper home maintenance will save you a lot of time, money, and hassle in the long run.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+The+Ultimate+Holiday+Home+Maintenance+Checklist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+The+Ultimate+Holiday+Home+Maintenance+Checklist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are you taking proper care of your home? Follow this home maintenance checklist
to make sure that your property stays in the best shape possible.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are you taking proper care of your home? Follow this home maintenance checklist
to make sure that your property stays in the best shape possible.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Should Do Before Buying a Vacation Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-should-do-before-buying.html</link>
        
          <category>Charleston</category>
        
          <category>Retirement</category>
        
          <category>Vacation Properties</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-09 14:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+What+You+Should+Do+Before+Buying+a+Vacation+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s never too early to begin planning your vacation home purchase.
Here’s what you need to know, whether you’re buying tomorrow or 10 years from now.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


If you’ve been wanting to buy a vacation home (or a permanent one), today we’re going to teach you everything you’ll need to know. We’ll also show you the top 10 best places to buy, so if you don’t have an idea in mind yet, we can give you some great suggestions. Before you decide to purchase your perfect getaway, here are some things to keep in mind.

The market is great, and people who have bought in the last few years have seen their equity skyrocket. There are a variety of loans available, and many don’t necessarily need huge down payments. Even if it’s something you’re simply thinking about, it’s a good idea to see if you’re qualified and find out what your affordability is like. It’s never too early to start planning.

Do research on the area you’re interested in. Is it a seasonal place or does it see traffic year round? What is the market doing? You want to purchase at the right time. You also want to go in with a plan, whether you’re wanting to purchase immediately or years from now. You can even leverage your home as a rental or Airbnb for when you’re not there. There are many different options that can help you pay for your property instead of having to wait and save.

“Go in with a plan, whether you’re wanting to purchase immediately or years from now.”

Don’t have an idea of where to buy? Here are the top 10 places to retire:


  Lakeland, Florida
  Dallas Fort Worth, Texas
  San Antonio, Texas
  Nashville, Tennessee
  Grand Rapids, Michigan
  Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
  Austin, Texas
  Sarasota, Florida
  Fort Meyers, Florida
  Lancaster, Pennsylvania


If you need help making a plan, figuring out your numbers, or buying your perfect property, feel free to reach out to us. We have some great agents who will put you on the perfect path toward your vacation home goals. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+What+You+Should+Do+Before+Buying+a+Vacation+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+What+You+Should+Do+Before+Buying+a+Vacation+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It’s never too early to begin planning your vacation home purchase.
Here’s what you need to know, whether you’re buying tomorrow or 10 years from now.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s never too early to begin planning your vacation home purchase.
Here’s what you need to know, whether you’re buying tomorrow or 10 years from now.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Wait Until Spring: You Can Sell This Winter!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-wait-until-spring-you-can-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-25 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Why wait until spring when you can sell just as well now?
We’ll show you why winter is a great time to list.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


We often have people asking around this season, “Should we sell now or wait until the first of the year?” There are a few points we like to look at to help sellers make that decision. A lot of it also comes down to determining your personal situation and how it plays into what we know about end-of-year statistics.

One thing we know is that there’s less competition toward the end of the year. This means a lot of people do believe they should sell after the new year instead, but it also means that buyers have fewer homes to choose from if you list now. This will ensure your house automatically stands out as a choice for homebuyers.

People are also being relocated or deciding to move. A common moving time is during summer, but another one is around the holidays. Companies tend to move employees before January, allowing families to enroll their children in the second half of the school year. Because there is this time limit, buyers are more motivated and serious in their search around this time. They want to make a quick transition.

“Your house automatically stands out as a choice for homebuyers.”

The holidays are a great time of year to showcase your home. On top of your decorations, you can show the sense of community your neighborhood holds. We go all out here in Santa Clarita during the holidays, so it’s a great time for people to see your home and those around it in fully decorated splendor.

On top of all this, mortgage rates are still low, and you’ll have quicker transactions and transitions when your home is sold. Buyers want to be settled before Thanksgiving, Christmas, or New Year’s. They’re willing to make great offers and move fast, allowing you to also get to your new residence quickly.

It comes down to what’s best for you and your family, and we’d be more than happy to help you decide what to do. Give us a call and we can walk you through the process. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Why wait until spring when you can sell just as well now?
We’ll show you why winter is a great time to list.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Why wait until spring when you can sell just as well now?
We’ll show you why winter is a great time to list.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats Going on in the Santa Clarita Market Right Now?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-santa-clarita-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-09 14:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Santa+Clarita+Market+Right+Now%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our market is shifting, but what does that mean for you? Keep reading to find out.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


We haven’t done a market update in a while, so I wanted to get one to you today about what’s going on right now in our local and national real estate markets.

In Santa Clarita, there are about 690 active homes on the market right now that are available for sale. Over the last 30 days, there have been 262 home sales.

If we look at the numbers over the last few months, we’re beginning to see a pattern of leveling out. We’ve been so used to extreme highs and lows over the past decade, but every sign is showing that the market is balancing out now. This normal, “boring” appreciation between 2% to 4% a year is good news for our market overall.

“There is opportunity for everyone in this market.”

We don’t exactly know how long this is going to last, but because our low inventory is gradually increasing and interest rates are bumping up slowly, we’re in a very equal and balanced market.

In any shifting market like this, there is opportunity for everyone. Whether you’re looking to move up, move down, invest, or buy your first home, there’s opportunity out here as long as you know where to look.

If you have any questions for us about how you can take advantage of this market, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Santa+Clarita+Market+Right+Now%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Whats+Going+on+in+the+Santa+Clarita+Market+Right+Now%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Our market is shifting, but what does that mean for you? Keep reading to find out.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Our market is shifting, but what does that mean for you? Keep reading to find out.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Exempt Yourself From Paying Capital Gains on Equity</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-exempt-yourself-from-paying.html</link>
        
          <category>1031 Exchange</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-29 12:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Have+Equity%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I am explaining the requirements for a capital gain exemption and a 1031 exchange.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


In this market, where properties carry a lot of equity, it is important to know everything you can about real estate investments. To help you out, I want to talk about capital gain exemption rules and 1031 exchanges with you today.

To start with, I will explain how capital gain exemptions work.

If you have lived at least two of the last five years in your current home, any equity you have built during that time can be claimed as tax-exempt gains. For married couples selling their home, this amount can go up to $500,000. A single person, on the other hand, can claim up to $250,000. You can even qualify for this exemption if you rented out your home for three of the years, as long as you currently live in the residence.

“If you have already made a capital gain exemption, you can still qualify if you have lived in your current home for two of the last five years.”

So, if you’re thinking about selling, this exemption can save you a lot of money.

And through a 1031 exchange, you can defer all capital gain taxes if you are thinking about selling your current investment property to reinvest the funds into a new one. Of course, this exchange doesn’t apply to primary residences. It must be done with investment properties.

If you have any questions about this, or if you are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Have+Equity%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Have+Equity%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I am explaining the requirements for a capital gain exemption and a 1031 exchange.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I am explaining the requirements for a capital gain exemption and a 1031 exchange.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Price Reductions Arent the Beginning of an Overall Trend</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-price-reductions-arent-beginning-of.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-13 14:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Why+Price+Reductions+Arent+the+Beginning+of+Overall+Trend.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Though we’ve seen some price reductions in our market, prices aren’t dropping overall.
Here’s why.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


We’ve seen a lot of price reductions lately in our Santa Clarita area, but does that mean the market’s leveling downward as a whole? We don’t believe so, and here’s why.

Most of these price reductions happened with listings whose sellers tried pricing their homes just ahead of the pace of the market while it was at an incline. For example, during this time, one of these sellers might’ve priced their home at $525,000 if they saw that the last home in their neighborhood sold at $500,000 and they thought theirs was better.

“Most of these price reductions happened with listings whose sellers tried pricing their homes just ahead of the pace of the market.”

As our market’s leveled out a bit, the excess demand for standing inventory has also leveled out. Now when we see that $525,000 home selling at—say—$510,000, what might look like an overall trend is actually the case of a seller reducing their price to a point that it should have been at all along.

If you have any more questions about our Santa Clarita market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Why+Price+Reductions+Arent+the+Beginning+of+Overall+Trend.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+Why+Price+Reductions+Arent+the+Beginning+of+Overall+Trend.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Though we’ve seen some price reductions in our market, prices aren’t dropping overall.
Here’s why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Though we’ve seen some price reductions in our market, prices aren’t dropping overall.
Here’s why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Closer Look at the Santa Clarita Real Estate Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-closer-look-at-santa-clarita-real.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-01 15:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+A+Closer+Look+at+the+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The Santa Clarita real estate market is starting to change. Here’s what you need to know.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


We’ve been seeing some changes lately in the market, so today we wanted to highlight a few things that you need to pay attention to, both in Santa Clarita and in the nationwide market.

Inventory is starting to rebuild, which we haven’t seen in a long time in Santa Clarita. Over the last five to eight years, we were hovering in the range of 300 to 500 homes as far as inventory was concerned. Right now, we have about 650 active homes on the market. At the same time, 330 homes have sold in the last 30 days, so the market is still healthy and normal.

As our inventory rebuilds, and should interest rates continue to tick up, this will knock out purchasing power for certain buyers. At this point, there’s only one thing for sellers in the market to do: be more competitive. In most cases, if the buyer pool starts to thin out, sellers need to be more competitive. Homes just aren’t selling as quickly as they have been.

“Homes that are priced right are still selling quickly and with multiple offers.”

In addition to this, we are seeing homes that are upgraded and priced right moving quickly and often selling with multiple offers. A lot of “experts” are saying that the market is going to start pulling back in the next year, while others are saying that we have another five to seven years of growth because of the economy.

At this point, we won’t know if the market has pulled back or not until three months after it has happened. What we do know is that it’s always important to have a game plan in place. Whether that is using the equity in your home to invest, possibly moving out of the area, upsizing, downsizing, and what options you have and what upgrades you can do.

No matter what your situations is, we’d love to work with you to develop a game plan. There’s no reason to panic right now, but it’s always important to have a contingency plan. If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email anytime. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Email This

BlogThis!

Share to Twitter

Share to Facebook

Share to Pinterest
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+A+Closer+Look+at+the+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+-+A+Closer+Look+at+the+Santa+Clarita+Real+Estate+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The Santa Clarita real estate market is starting to change. Here’s what you need to know.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The Santa Clarita real estate market is starting to change. Here’s what you need to know.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Trust a Zestimate?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-you-trust-zestimate.html</link>
        
          <category>Zillow</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-19 13:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Can+You+Trust+a+Zestimate%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Though popular, Zillow and similar real estate websites can’t really provide you the same, accurate information that a Realtor can. Here’s why.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


Are home valuation tools like Zillow’s Zestimate accurate? Can you count on that information when determining how much equity you have, what your home’s value is, and what’s going on in the neighborhood?

We hear questions like these regarding those online tools all the time. The truth is, if you’re just trying to get a general idea of the neighborhood values, a Zestimate might get you close. However, I’ve seen many instances in which Zestimates price a home $50,000 to $100,000 higher or lower than they ought to have per the market.

Zestimates and their like determine the value of your home based on an algorithm that incorporates the information of comparable home sales in the area. It can’t take into account the fact that, say, your community is gated, or if it’s located in a tract that borders another tract; one low sale in a neighboring tract can throw your Zestimate off completely.

Additionally, Zillow can’t analyze what’s inside of your home, so it can’t take into account any upgrades and improvements you’ve done that might affect your value. It also doesn’t factor in the condition of the properties surrounding your home. If your home is a model match for the one next door, but yours has been upgraded where the other hasn’t, the Zestimate won’t be able to see the difference.

“Zillow can’t analyze what’s inside of your home, so it can’t take into account any upgrades and improvements you’ve done that might affect your value.”

Finally, these online valuation tools won’t consider the amount of inventory in your area. Many markets like ours are lacking in inventory, which causes prices to push in a positive direction, especially for homes with the right upgrades.

If the numbers you get back from the Zestimate seem too good to be true, chances are that the numbers are off. That’s where you reach out to a real estate professional like us. We are more than happy to pull some basic numbers and give you a much more accurate ballpark estimate of your home’s value. We can also come out to your house to take a peek and factor in your current or future upgrades to determine the eventual price your home could get.

If you need assistance from us or have any questions, please feel free to lean on us and make our team your No. 1 resource. We’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Can+You+Trust+a+Zestimate%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Can+You+Trust+a+Zestimate%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Though popular, Zillow and similar real estate websites can’t really provide you the same, accurate information that a Realtor can. Here’s why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Though popular, Zillow and similar real estate websites can’t really provide you the same, accurate information that a Realtor can. Here’s why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Get the Most From Your Future Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-get-most-from-your-future-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-04 13:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/How+to+Get+the+Most+From+Your+Future+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What can you do to get the most money out of your home when it comes time to sell? Here’s my advice to future home sellers.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


You’re thinking about selling your home in the next two to five years—what should you be doing between now and then to ensure that you get the most value out of your home as possible when it comes time to sell?

We have many ways to approach this problem. We are more than happy to come out to your house and discuss value-adding upgrades and upgrades that will be a poor investment. Having an agent’s help in that area will itself prove invaluable, since not every home will have same upgrades to boost its worth.

We can also send you our blank home inspection list. If you can start checking projects and repairs off that list sooner than later, it will save you a lot of time and stress when it comes time to list your home.

“It’s not a bad idea to get the serious projects taken care of while you have time to space them out.”

Additionally, we can connect you with a home inspector if you’d like a pre-inspection. With a pre-inspection, you can find out what things are likely to pop up during the official inspection, which also allows you to address problems before you actually get to the transaction.

If something were to come up during the transaction, you potentially run the risk of holding it up, lowering your net profits, or even cancelling it altogether, depending on what the issue is. Issues with safety and home integrity are going to be the most unattractive features for buyers to see. It’s not a bad idea to get the serious projects taken care of while you have time to space them out.

If you have any questions about value-adding upgrades and getting your home ready for the process of listing, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’ll be glad to come out and take a look and create a plan for you to move forward toward your goal of selling your home for the most money possible.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/How+to+Get+the+Most+From+Your+Future+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/How+to+Get+the+Most+From+Your+Future+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What can you do to get the most money out of your home when it comes time to sell? Here’s my advice to future home sellers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What can you do to get the most money out of your home when it comes time to sell? Here’s my advice to future home sellers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Santa Clarita Valley Market Update for Spring 2018</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/santa-clarita-valley-market-update-for.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Santa Clarita</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-22 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Market+Update+for+Spring+2018.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We have a quick market update for you today. Here is what you should know about the current state of Santa Clarita Valley real estate.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


It is starting to heat up out there in the Santa Clarita Valley. Summer is around the corner, and so is the peak buying season for our real estate market. We haven’t given you a market update in a while, so I wanted to give you a quick update on the latest numbers and where we’re at.

Inventory is something you’ve probably been hearing about a lot. Over the last few years, we have been hovering at very low levels. We are nowhere near where a balanced market should be. Right now, we have 452 active listings on the market to go along with 517 pending sales.

Over the last 30 days, we have had 317 closed home sales. Anything over 300 is a great number. The interesting thing about our inventory is that of the 452 homes, 252 of them have been on the market for less than 30 days. More than half of our inventory is fairly new. At the same time, 96 homes have been on the market for more than 60 days.

“We have seen 317 closed home sales over the last 30 days.”

Another factor we need to consider is interest rates. Even though they are creeping up, our low inventory and high demand brings a lot of opportunity to the market for buyers, sellers, and investors.

If you want to know more about the market and where we see it heading over the next year, give us a call or send us an email. We watch these things closely and would be happy to chat with you. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Market+Update+for+Spring+2018.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Market+Update+for+Spring+2018.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We have a quick market update for you today. Here is what you should know about the current state of Santa Clarita Valley real estate.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We have a quick market update for you today. Here is what you should know about the current state of Santa Clarita Valley real estate.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is It a Good Idea to Add Solar Panels to Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-it-good-idea-to-add-solar-panels-to.html</link>
        
          <category>Solar Energy</category>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-26 11:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Is+It+a+Good+Idea+to+Add+Solar+Panels+to+Your+Home%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Many people are curious as to whether solar panels add any dollar value to a property, so let’s explore this question today.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


People often ask my team and I, “Do solar panels add to a home’s value?” Alongside this question, people also often ask us whether it’s better to purchase or lease.

Unfortunately, solar panels do not appear to make an impact when it comes to adding a dollar value to your home. Appraisers have found that, because there are so many kinds of solar panels and so many means by which a person might purchase or lease them, the potential for added value is difficult to assess.

That being said, the presence of solar panels, whether they were purchased or leased, may increase the overall appeal of your home in the eyes of certain buyers. Solar panels that have been purchased outright are more likely to be usable as a bargaining chip in the transaction. Leased units, on the other hand, tend to prompt more hesitance from potential buyers.

“While they may not add dollar value, solar panels may increase the overall appeal of your home.”

So the bottom line is this: If you’re thinking of selling your home in the next few years, let us know and we can discuss whether adding solar panels to your property is the right choice for you.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Is+It+a+Good+Idea+to+Add+Solar+Panels+to+Your+Home%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Videos/Is+It+a+Good+Idea+to+Add+Solar+Panels+to+Your+Home%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Many people are curious as to whether solar panels add any dollar value to a property, so let’s explore this question today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Many people are curious as to whether solar panels add any dollar value to a property, so let’s explore this question today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Protect Your Home From Burglars</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-home-for-burglars.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-14 11:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate-+6+Things+Edited.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you protect your home from burglars? I have six tips to help you today.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


There is a burglary about every 20 seconds in the United States. Today, I have a few tips to help you prevent your home from becoming a target.

There are six main things that burglars don’t want you to know:

1. Burglaries don’t always happen at night. That’s what we see in the movies, but the majority of burglaries happen between 12:30 and 2:30 p.m. The last thing the criminal wants to do is run into you. Protecting yourself in the middle of the day is most important.

2. They know when you’re not home thanks to social media. If you’re on Facebook or Twitter, don’t post exactly where you are if you are out of the house or on vacation. They recently caught a burglar who hit 33 different homes. He simply watched his targets on social media and looked at the location when they posted a picture to determine whether the family was home or not. Be careful when posting photos, and don’t make a status update about your week-long vacation.

3. They don’t like your security practices. If there is an easily identifiable alarm system for your home, then your home is 300% less likely to be targeted. Floodlights, leaving a car in the driveway, leaving a TV on, and turning on the lights inside all help deter burglars.

4. Great targets advertise their weapon supply. Is there a bumper sticker on your car that says you own a weapon? There are a lot of burglars out there who are incentivized to steal weapons because they can sell them for a lot of money. Advertising your weapons can actually make you more of a target rather than deterring burglaries.

5. Shrubs and architecture make great hiding spots. If you have big shrubs in front of your house that someone can hide behind to get into your house, that’s not good. The more open your landscaping is, the less likely it is for someone to try to break into your home because a neighbor might spot them from the street. If you do want to plant something in front of your window, make sure that it’s something thorny that they won’t want to jump through to get to your home.

6. Don’t leave your valuables out in the open. A lot of the time, these criminals look through the windows to see if there are any laptops or stuff that’s easily accessible for them to go after. Put your valuables away. I also recommend hiding family calendars because those can advertise where you are going to be.

“DON’T ADVERTISE YOUR LOCATION ON SOCIAL MEDIA.”

I hope you found these tips helpful. I have something else to offer you today—one of my mentors and coaches, Steve Scanlon, just published his second book, “Still the Lizard.” It is an amazing read that explains what the lizard brain is and how it works.

If you want a free copy, be the first one to email me with the four traits of the lizard brain. (Hint: The answer can be found at www.rewireinc.com.)

As always, if you have any other real estate questions for me, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate-+6+Things+Edited.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate-+6+Things+Edited.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you protect your home from burglars? I have six tips to help you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you protect your home from burglars? I have six tips to help you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Money Saving Tips for Homeowners</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-few-money-saving-tips-for-homeowners.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Owner Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-28 15:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Saving money is easy as a homeowner. Here are seven tips that will help you save instantly.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


Today I’d like to give you a few tips for saving money around the house. These tips might seem silly or simple at first, but they can save you a lot of money over time and they’re often overlooked by sellers:

1. Make the switch to energy-efficient lighting. A standard incandescent lightbulb costs around $180 in electricity to operate each month. If you’re using a CFL or LED light, however, that’s only going to cost you $30 or $40. That’s $100+ in savings each month, and if you add up the totals for the life of the bulbs, the sum is enormous.

2. Fix leaky faucets right away. Even if a leaky faucet only drips one drop per second, that adds up to over 3,000 gallons in a year. By fixing those leaky faucets immediately, you can save a lot on your water bill.

3. Change your air filter regularly. When you let your filter get clogged up, it works overtime to compensate. That leaves you with dirtier air and a higher utility bill. Make sure your filter is changed every few months.

4. Custom temperatures. Whether it’s with a smart thermostat or an old-school programmable one, being able to set custom temperatures in your home for when you’re not there will save you thousands over the years.

5. Overwatering your yard. This will not only keep your water bills sky-high, but it could also cause damage to your lawn as well.

6. Pay attention to the water heater temperature. During warmer months, you can drop the temperature in your heater down a little bit to save you a bit more without affecting anything else.

7. Poorly sealed windows. If a window or door is letting in a draft, make sure you get it sealed with some caulk or weatherstripping to keep things insulated and keep your energy costs down.

These are just a few great ways to save money over time as a homeowner. If you have any questions for me or want any more tips, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Saving money is easy as a homeowner. Here are seven tips that will help you save instantly.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Saving money is easy as a homeowner. Here are seven tips that will help you save instantly.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Do If Your Property Taxes Are Too High?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-you-do-if-your-property.html</link>
        
          <category>Property Taxes</category>
        
        <author>Brandon Montemayor</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-31 13:21:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+Taxes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Tax season is officially here, and I want to go over a few important things you should know about property taxes.


Want to Buy a Home? Search All Homes
Want to Sell a Home? Get a Home Value Report


Tax season is here, so I want to discuss a few things about property taxes and what to do when you have some questions on those.

If you plan on buying anything or getting a loan in the next couple of years, how you file today or in the next few months will have a huge impact on what you qualify for on future loans.

People write off a lot of items. Whether you are a business owner or you have the ability to write income down or defer things, make sure you give us a call if you are thinking about buying an investment property or primary residence. We have to make sure that you have enough income on there to qualify for whatever home you are looking to purchase.

There are a few other things you should know with regard to property taxes.

July 1 is the beginning of the tax year for property taxes. October 1 is when tax bills are mailed. The first installment is due November 1. December 10 is the final due date you have to make if you don’t want to pay any penalties.

“IF YOUR PROPERTY TAX BILL IS TOO HIGH, WE CAN HELP YOU CHALLENGE IT.”

Then, the second installment is due February 1. April 10 is the last day for you to pay the second installment without penalties.

Then, June 30 is the end of the tax year, and everything starts back over on July 1.

If you get a property tax bill and you believe that it’s too high, let us know. We can help you challenge that.

If your property tax bill is too low, then keep that to yourself!

If you believe that your bank is supposed to pay your property taxes because you pay impounds, and that number seems to be off or there’s not enough in the escrow account to cover it, keep an eye on that stuff. This is especially important in the first few years of homeownership because the bank can go way off and end up having to assess you additional fees or bump your payment later on.

If you have any other questions about property taxes, just give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+Taxes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brandon+Montemayor/Santa+Clarita+Valley+Real+Estate+Taxes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Tax season is officially here, and I want to go over a few important things you should know about property taxes.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brandon Montemayor</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Tax season is officially here, and I want to go over a few important things you should know about property taxes.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Santa Clara, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Brandon Montemayor</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Brandon Montemayor</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Montemayor & Associates - your professional Santa Clara Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
